Inventory of the Oscar Meyer collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Oscar Meyer collection
1883-1952
2011C31
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box (0.4 linear feet)
Letters written by assorted prominent German political, academic and religious figures, mostly addressed to Friedrich Naumann or to Theodor Heuss.
Meyer, Oscar, 1876-1961
Access
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2011.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Letters written by assorted prominent German political, academic and religious figures, mostly addressed to Friedrich Naumann or to Theodor Heuss.
Heuss, Theodor, 1884-1963.; Naumann, Friedrich, 1860-1919.; Germany--Civilization.
- Friedrich Naumann Correspondence, 1892-1925, undated
  - Avenarius, F., 1919 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Ballin, 1908 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Bretand, 1901 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Deissmann, Adolf, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Delbrück, Hans, 1898, 1909 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Engel, Edourd, undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Ernst, Paul, 1901 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Francke, Ernst, 1912 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Freksa, Friedrich, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Friedjung, Heinrich, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Goetz, Walter, 1906 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Harden, Maximilian, undated (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Jastrow, Ignaz, 1897 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Kautsky, Karl, 1899 (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Kerschensteiner, Georg Michael, 1905 (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Klein, Franz, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Knapp, Georg, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Kulemann, Wilhelm, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Lamprecht, Karl, 1906 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Lenz, Max, 1913 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Lissauer, Ernst, undated (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Lotz, Walter, 1909 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Maurenbrecher, Max, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Mommsen, Karl, 1914 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Morf, Heinrich, 1914 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Muser, Oskar, 1913 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Oppenheimer, Franz, 1910 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Paulsen, Friedrich, 1906 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Philippsohn, E., 1915 (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Potthoff, Heinz, 1910 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Preuss, Hugo, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Quark, Max, 1893 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Rade, Paul, 1919 (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - Ratheman, Walter, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - Rickert, Heinrich, 1909 (Box-folder 1: 36)
  - Rohrbach, Paul, 1908 (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - Schulze-Gaevernitz, Gerhart von, 1897, 1903 (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - Smend, Julius, 1892 (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - Soden, Hermann von, 1896 (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - Sohm, Rudolf, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - Sonnemann, Leopold, 1893 (Box-folder 1: 42)
  - Titus, Arthur, undated (Box-folder 1: 43)
  - Tonnies, Ferdinand, 1897, 1902 (Box-folder 1: 44)
  - Traub, Gottfried, undated (Box-folder 1: 45)
  - Viebig, Clara, 1902 (Box-folder 1: 46)
  - Voigt, Andreas, 1897 (Box-folder 1: 47)
  - Warburg, Max, 1906 (Box-folder 1: 48)
  - Wagner, Adolf, 1895 (Box-folder 1: 49)
  - Weber, Max, undated (Box-folder 1: 50)
  - Weber, Alfred, 1925 (Box-folder 1: 51)
  - Wilamowitz-Moellendorf, U., undated (Box-folder 1: 52)
  - Wolf, Theodor, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 1: 53)
  - Woltmann, Ludwig, 1900 (Box-folder 1: 54)
  - unidentified, 1911 (Box-folder 1: 55)
- Theodor Heuss Correspondence, 1890-1937, undated
  - Broemel, Max, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 56)
  - Cauer, Minna, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 57)
  - Charmatz, Richard, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 58)
  - Dibelius, Martin, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 59)
  - Flaischlen Cäsar, 1905 (Box-folder 1: 60)
  - Funck, Wilhelm, 1912 (Box-folder 1: 61)
  - Halben, Herman, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 62)
  - Heilfron, Edaurd, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 63)
  - Jantzen, Viktor, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 64)
  - Kern Fritz, 1916 (Box-folder 1: 65)
  - Lantman [?], E., 1937 (Box-folder 1: 66)
  - Lenz, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 67)
  - Levysohn, Arthur, undated (Box-folder 1: 68)
  - Liebert, Edaurd von, 1908 (Box-folder 1: 69)
  - Liebmann, Otto, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 70)
  - Lieslhing, Theodor, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 71)
  - Mugdan, Otto, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 72)
  - Nathan, Paul, 1917 (Box-folder 1: 73)
  - Nobbe, Moritz A., 1890 (Box-folder 1: 74)
  - Paquet, Alfons, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 75)
  - Rade, Paul Martin, 1920 (Box-folder 1: 76)
  - Scawitzer, Albert, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 77)
  - Weitzoldt, Wilhelm, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 78)
  - Weber, Marianne, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 79)
  - Wilbrandt, Robert, 1901 (Box-folder 1: 80)
- General Correspondence, 1883-1952
  - Aegidi, Ludwig Karl, 1883 (Box-folder 1: 81)
  - Bülow, Albert, 1920 (Box-folder 1: 82)
  - Düring, Ernst von, 1817 (Box-folder 1: 83)
  - Geiger, Ludwig, 1896 (Box-folder 1: 84)
  - Hellmann, Ernst, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 85)
  - Jentsen, Carl, 1900 (Box-folder 1: 86)
  - Lippmann, Julius, 1932 (Box-folder 1: 87)
  - Mantoux, Paul, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 88)
  - Meyer, Heinrich, 1904 (Box-folder 1: 89)
  - Naumann, 1898 (Box-folder 1: 90)
  - Niemann, August, 1908 (Box-folder 1: 91)
  - Nuschke, Otto, 1920 (Box-folder 1: 92)
  - Rabel, Ernst, 1940 (Box-folder 1: 93)
  - Seyda, Wladislaw, 1912 (Box-folder 1: 94)
  - Stein, August, 1907 (Box-folder 1: 95)
  - Steinhal, Max, 1913 (Box-folder 1: 96)
  - Stephany, Friedrich, 1912 (Box-folder 1: 97)
  - Vierhaus, Felix, 1917 (Box-folder 1: 98)
  - Vogelsang, Theodor, 1917 (Box-folder 1: 99)
  - Vorlaender, Karl, 1915 (Box-folder 1: 100)
  - Warburg, Max, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 101)
  - Wertheimer, Edaurd, 1913 (Box-folder 1: 102)
  - unidentified, 1908-1952, undated (Box-folder 1: 103)